A Guide to the Alfred Ezra Mirsky papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA131
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Conferences, meetings, seminars, 1951-1962; 5
  - Cambridge, England The Faraday Society meeting on The Cell Nucleus, 1959 August 31-September 1 (Box 43)
    Mirsky "Some problems in the study of nuclear enzymes" Allfrey "Amino acid activation and transfer to ribonucleic acids in the cell nucleus".
    Correspondence; program; typescript drafts; Mirsky handwritten outline and reprint.
  - NY City 4th Annual meeting Eastern Psychiatric Research Assoc. Symposium on the genetics of disordered behavior, 1959 October 24 (Box 43)
    Mirsky and Allfrey "Biochemical activities of the cell nucleus".
    Program; correspondence; typescript and handwritten drafts.
  - New York State Society for Medical Research Course in modern aspects of biology to NY City High School biology teachers in NY City (2 lectures) (Box 43)
    - Mirsky "Structure and function of the cell nucleus", 1959 December 10
      Correspondence; handwritten outline; program.
    - Mirsky "Function of the cell nucleus", 1960 November 17
      Typescript outline and program.
  - Santiago, University of Chile. Over-all title: Some problems of the cell nucleus, 1960 January 4-17 (Box 43)
    Includes correspondence; handwritten outlines; assorted reprints.
    Mirsky (5 seminars):.
    - "The concept of epigenesis", 1960 January 4
    - "Epigenesis as seen in protein synthesis", 1960 January 6
    - "Chemistry of the cell nucleus", 1960 January 8
    - "Synthesis in the nucleus", 1960 January 11
    - "Interactions between nucleus and cytoplasm", 1960 January 13
  - Chicago, Ill. B.S.C.S. Publications committee meeting, 1960 March 18 (Box 43)
    Memo on travel expense and honorarium.
  - Oklahoma City, Oklahoma Symposium on origins of life for high school students and adults cosponsored by AIBS and The Frontiers of Science Foundation of Oklahoma, 1960 April 1 (Box 43)
    Correspondence; handwritten outline.
  - Stillwater, Oklahoma, Oklahoma State University Mirsky (2 talks), 1960 April 22-23 (Box 43)
    - "Interactions within the cell", April 22
    - "The role of magnesium in the cell nucleus", April 23
    - Correspondence; handwritten outlines
  - Amsterdam, The Netherlands International Symposium on biosynthesis of proteins, 1960 August 29-September 2 (Box 43)
    Allfrey and Mirsky "Amino acid transport into the cell nucleus and reactions governing nuclear protein synthesis".
    Correspondence; typescript draft; photographs; abstracts of presented papers.
  - Paris, X International Congress for Cell Biology, 1960 September 4-9 (Box 43)
    Mirsky and Allfrey "Rapports entre la structure fine des gènes et leur expression biochimique au niveau moleculaire".
  - Washington, DC National Science Foundation Review panel on summer science training program for secondary school students, 1960 October 10-11 (Box 43)
    Correspondence; typescript draft of part of discussion.
  - Cornell University Medical College, Department of Physiology seminar, 1960 November 19 (Box 43)
    Correspondence; Hempling ms.
  - Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons, Institute of Cancer Research, 1961 January 14 (Box 43)
    Mirsky "The chemistry of the cell nucleus" Correspondence; cancelled due to illness.
  - Princeton, N.J. Conference on science information, 1961 March 5-7 (Box 43)
    Mirsky on Communication - transfer of information within the cell.
    Correspondence; handwritten outline of talk to journalsts.
  - Moscow, V International Congress of Biochemistry, 1961 August 10-16 (Box 43)
    Mirsky "The Cell Nucleus".
    Allfrey "Observations on the mechanism and control of protein synthesis in the cell nucleus".
    Correspondence (a considerable amount on planning); typescript and handwritten drafts; reprint of Allfrey paper.
  - Denver AAAS Symposium on phvsiological and biochemical aspects of human genetics, 1961 December 29-30 (Box 43)
    Mirsky "Structure and specific action of DNA".
  - Munich, Gesellschaft Deutscher Naturforscher und Arzte, 1962 September 9-13 (Box 43)
    Mirsky "Interactions between nucleus and cytoplasm" (in German).
    Correspondence; typescript draft; galley proof; program; abstract (in English).
  - University of Delhi and All-India Institute of Medical Sciences giving talks. Under sponsorship of Rockefeller Foundation visited 14 Indian laboratories, 1963 January 1-February 11; [1/2" folder] (Box 43)
    Correspondence; typescript and handwritten drafts of report to Rockefeller Foundation on visits to Indian laboratories; photocopy of Indian newspaper interview.
  - Rancho Sante Fe, Calif. 1st World Conference on histone biology and chemistry, 1963 April 29-May 2 (Box 43)
    Allfrey and Mirsky "Role of histone in nuclear function".
    Correspondence; participants and program. [Ed. note: Title from bibliography].
  - Glasgow, Scotland The University, 1963 May 29 (Box 43)
    Mirsky "Some observations on lampbrush chromosomes".
    Correspondence (some with Callan concerning visit to St. Andrews).
  - Wakulla Springs, Fla. Conference on the origin of prebiological systems and their molecular matrices, 1963 October 27-30 (Box 43)
    Mirsky "Chairman's remarks".
    Correspondence; program; galley proof.
  - Hyderbad, India, Regional Research Laboratory Symposium on nucleic acids. [Ed. note: Information from bibliography], 1964 (Box 43)
    Mirsky, Allfrey and Faulkner "Some recent experiments on the role of histones as regulators of chromosomal activity".
    Typescript draft; working reprint.
  - NY City Biltmore Hotel, New York Heart Assoc. Symposium on differentiation and development, 1964 February 7-8 (Box 44)
    Mirsky "Regulation of genetic expression; general survey".
    Correspondence; transcript of discussion; typescript and handwritten drafts; printer's copy.
  - University of Palermo, Italy. Mirsky (2 lectures): "Genetics and human nature", 1964 April 22-24 (Box 44)
    "Variable chromosomal activity".
    Typescript and handwritten drafts of what appears to be "Genetics and human affairs"; printed announcements; handwritten outlines.
  - Saskatoon, University of Saskatchewan, 9th Annual Meeting of the Genetics Society of Canada, 1964 May 7-9 (Box 44)
    Mirsky on the science of heredity Handwritten outlines;.
    program.
  - Houston, Texas 19th Annual Symposium on fundamental cancer research at the M.D. Anderson Hospital and Tumor Institute, 1965 March 4-6 (Box 44)
    Mirsky "Protein factors in genetic regulation - a current evaluation".
    Correspondence; abstract; cancelled due to wife illness.
  - Columbia University, 1965 March 18 (Box 44)
    - Mirsky "Some thoughts on the present state of biology" Thank you note
    - 1965 October 19, Typescript and handwritten drafts with corrections; also handwritten outline headed with Columbia University
  - New York State University Conference on the trends and future of the biological and related sciences and the consequent nature of a desirable university curriculum, held at RU, 1965 November 26-27 (Box 44)
    Mirsky "The importance of chemistry to cellular physiology and to the new biology".
  - London, Ciba Foundation Study Group on The role of histones in the transfer of genetic information. Meeting honoring W.A. Engelhardt of USSR, 1965 (Box 44)
    Mirsky "Chairman's introduction".
    Pogo, Pogo, Kleinsmith and Mirsky "The metabolic behaviour of chromatin" delivered by Allfrey.
    Correspondence; program; typescript draft of Mirsky introduction and general discussion; handwritten draft of outline and discussion; typescript draft of paper delivered by Allfrey.
  - RU Christmas Lectures for selected high school students from the metropolitan area and nearby suburbs, 1965 December 27-30 (Box 44)
    Mirsky and Allfrey "The cell nucleus - kernel of life".
    [Ed. note: see oversize file for RNA artwork; also see Box no. 45 for reels of film for these lectures; also negatives of lecture illustrations].
    Includes typescript draft of welcome to students; typescript and handwritten outlines for six lectures; lecture I, II, III typescript and handwritten drafts; lecture IV typescript and handwritten outline; figure and negatives.
  - Minneapolis, University of Minnesota course in genetics and medicine, 1966 March 23-26 (Box 44)
    Mirsky "Protein factors in genetic regulation" Correspondence; abstract.
  - University of Palermo, Italy2nd International Summer course on Advances in experimental embryology - Activation of genes in the embryonic development, 1967 September 25-October 14 (Box 44)
    Mirsky - Chairman.
    Allfrey and Davidson participants.
    Program (see also Box 12 Reverberi correspondence).
  - Tübingen, Miescher Centennial Symposium, 1969 (Box 44)
    Mirsky "The historical background of Miescher's discovery".
    Typescript and handwritten drafts of ms and outline (see also Box 5 Beermann correspondence).
  - Ethical Culture Society, NY City (2 lectures) (Box 44)
    - Felix Adler Lecture, 1970 May 21
      Mirsky "Heredity - environment interaction and the nature of man".
      Typescript draft (see also Box 7 Ethical Culture Society correspondence).
    - Mirsky "Our genes: heredity and environment", 1972 March 19
      Typescript drafts; (see also box 7 Ethical Culture Society correspondence).
  - Washington DC IV International Congress of Endocrinology, 1972 June 18-24 (Box 44)
    Mirsky Chairman of symposium on "Hormones and differentiation".
  - RU Seminar on the ontogeny of behavior, 1973 November 13 (Box 44)
  - Mirsky "Genetics of behavioral development" (Box 44)
    Correspondence; bibliography.
  - NY City, Nat'l Assoc. of Biology Teachers Convention, 1974 October 12-14 (Box 44)
    Mirsky "Interaction between genes and environment".
    Correspondence; scheduled to speak.
  - Miscellaneous - Group of items which refer to meetings. No evidence as to actual attendance (Box 44)
    - Tokyo and Kyoto, Japan International Genetics Symposia, 1956 September 6-12
    - Osaka, Japan Symposium on structure and function of nucleic acids, 1956 September 13
      Mirsky asked to present same paper at both.
      Correspondence; announcements.
    - Chalois, 1961 August 27
      Mirsky "The control of genetic activity".
    - New Haven also Ann Arbor, 1964 February
      Handwritten outline Rochester Handwritten outline.
  - Special Course: New School for Social Research lecture course, 1949 February 8-May 17 (Box 44)
    Mirsky notebook outlining and describing 14 lectures (absent from lecture 10 - no description).
  - Addresses - Ph.D. Presentations (Box 44)
    - Eric Davidson, 1963 June; Typescript draft
    - Peter Wolk (Armin C. Braun student), 1964 June; typescript and handwritten drafts
    - Rosemary Faulkner, 1966 June; typescript draft
    - Caleb E. Finch, 1969 June; Typescript draft
  - Addresses - D.W. Bronk retirement (Box 44)
    - Presentation upon retirement from presidency of RU; gift of books, 1968 June
    - Typescript draft with corrections; working material
  - RU Christmas Lectures, 1965 (Box 45)
    Mirsky and Allfrey "The cell nucleus - kernel of life" 5 reels of film: 4 in metal containers; 1 in brown paper; description on each reel of film (See Box no. 44 for typescript and additional information).
- Laboratory notes, 1928-1974; 6
  Includes notes, charts, graphs, summaries, and photographs.
  Arranged in approximate chronological order.
  - Laboratory procedure guides and chart from laboratory bulletin board, [undated] (Box 46)
  - Methods and recipes; methods 2 spiral notebooks, [undated] (Box 46)
  - Hemoglobin 1 bound black notebook, 1928-1932 (Box 46)
  - Pepsin, 1930 (Box 46)
  - Globulin, serum, edestin, Hb, insulin, 1930-1933 (Box 46)
  - Egg albumin, 1931-1937 (Box 46)
  - Fibrin, 1931-1933 (Box 46)
  - Serum albumin, 1930-1935 (Box 46)
    Includes Mirsky and Anson ms "Letter to The Editor: of Nature (no evidence of publication) with 2 Hopkins published papers.
  - Nails, 1933 (Box 46)
  - Miscellaneous, 1933-1939 (Box 46)
    Includes notes on tyrosine, triptophane, edestin and K ferri, gelatine, zein, myosin, nitrogen, phosphate buffers, egg albumin, cysteine.
  - Keratin, 1936 (Box 46)
  - Muscle, 1931-1937 (Box 46)
  - Muscle, 1940 (Box 47)
    Mirsky letter to the Editor of J. Biological Chemistry submitting note "Sulfhydryl group of denatured egg albumin" (no evidence of publication) typescript and handwritten drafts of note; also other workers reprints.
  - Myosin SH, 1939-1941; 1 notebook (Box 47)
  - Egg albumin, 1939-1941; 3 notebooks (Box 47)
  - Calibration, 1939-1949; 1 notebook (Box 47)
  - Plasmosin, 1941-1942; 1 notebook (Box 47)
  - Chromatin, 1942; 1 notebook (Box 47)
  - Nucleo proteins, 1942-1944; 2 notebooks (Box 47)
  - Bacteriology, 1943-1944; 1 notebook (Box 47)
  - Miscellaneous, 1943-1945 (Box 47)
    Includes 3 outlines.
  - Thymus citric acid nuclei, 1945 March-May (Box 47)
  - Literature searches, 2 notebooks (Box 47)
  - Liver, thymus chromosomes, 1946 January-July (Box 47)
    Notes copied into bound black book (see pkg. 47a in brown paper).
  - Chromosomes, 1946-1947 (Box 47)
    Includes outlines.
  - Thymus nuclei; liver and thymus chromosomes, 1944-1946 1946-1947; 2 bound black notebooks 47a is a pkg. in brown paper (Box 47a)
  - Experiments on liver, thymus, pancreas, kidney, 1947-1952; 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Staining with crystal violet, 1948-1949 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - RNA fetal pancreas and liver, 1951-1952 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Thymus chromosomes, 1947-1948 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Using Calf, horse, swine, rabbit, sheep (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Rooster sperm (original folder title), 1948-1949 (Box 48)
    Correspondence on experimental work.
    Includes notes on other sperm.
  - Chromosomes constituents as antigens (G. Gasic notes), 1949 (Box 48)
    Includes typescript draft of Materials and Methods.
  - Amino acid composition, 1944-1945 1948-1950 (Box 48)
  - Chromatograms, 1948-1950; 2 folders (Box 48)
    Mixture of nucleic acid bases.
  - Composition of isolated nuclei, 1949-1951; 2 folders (Box 49)
    Typescript description called "Microscopic observation of Amphiuma erythrocytes".
  - Enzyme activities, 1950-1951 (Box 49)
    Includes reprints of others.
    Includes letter from G. Gomori.
  - Nuclei, 1953-1954 (Box 49)
    Includes reprints of N.B. Kurnick and H. Ris; N.B. Kurnick and A.E. Mirsky.
  - Chromatography of nucleotides, 1943-1956 (Box 49)
    Charts dealing with.
  - Mass spectrometer sheets, 1952-1953; 2 folders (Box 50, Folder 1-2)
  - Chromatography of amino acids and histones, 1952 1953 (Box 50)
  - Mouse pancreas in vitro experiments, 1952-1953 (Box 50)
  - Action of RNAase on mouse pancreas, 1952 (Box 50)
  - Sucrose pellet - mouse pancreas; liver, 1953 (Box 50)
  - N¹⁵ incorporation into pellets "normal" + cortisone, 1953 (Box 50)
  - Incorporation of N¹⁵ glycine and orotic acid into nuclear components, 1953-1954 (Box 50)
  - Measurements in feeding and fasting experiments: Glucose - non-glucose of incorporation; DNA and RNA content, 1954 (Box 50)
  - Electrophoresis work and tables: Original folders labelled Fox, ?? I and II Pancreas - trypsin, chymotrypsin - electrophoresis (Folder I) N¹⁵ uptake tables - pancreas, liver, kidney (Folder II) 1952,1953,1954 Histones - chromatograms (Box 50)
  - Electrophoresis of histones tiselius and zone, 1952 1953 1954 (Box 51)
  - Histones + instructions of fractionation, 1952 1954 1956 (Box 51)
  - Histone fractions, 1953 1954; 2 folders (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
  - Extractions of mouse and beef pancreas for chromatography, 1953 1954 (Box 51)
  - Trypsin - inhibitor reactions attempt to purify trypsin, 1953-1954 (Box 51)
  - Pellet protein chromatograms amino acid analysis, 1953-1954 (Box 51)
  - Chromatography of histones on IRC-50, 1954-1955 (Box 51)
    Includes typescript draft of "Chromatographic fractionation of calf thymus histone" by Crampton, Moore and Stein; typescript description on procedure of "Chromatography of histones on Ca IRC-50".
  - Nucleotides (miscellaneous data), 1955-1956 (Box 51)
    Includes chromatography of.
  - Chromatography of nucleotides (Continued in Box 52), 1955-1956 (Box 51)
  - Chromatography of nucleotides, 1953 1955-1956; 5 folders (Box 52)
    Folders labelled consecutively: 1-5 but no clear chronological order.
  - Chromatography of nucleotides, 1957 (Box 53)
  - TCA - protein experiments (lysine - histone + nucleotides), 1954 1956 (Box 53)
  - Effect of acetate on nucleotides, 1956 (Box 53)
  - Protein fractionation of thymus sucrose nuclei, 1954-1956 (Box 53)
  - Thymus sucrose nuclei experiments (a few items from 1960), 1954-1956 (Box 53)
  - Assorted nuclei experiments - liver, kidney, thymus, 1956-1957 (Box 53)
  - Incorporation of alanine-1-C¹⁴ into liver nuclei, 1957-1958 (Box 53)
    Includes typescript on procedure.
  - Resuspension; analysis of mouse liver sucrose nuclei, 1957-1958 (Box 53)
  - Analysis of calcium by Versene method Typescript draft supplied by Dr. Rich on procedure of, 1959 January (Box 53)
  - Preparations, analyses of various nuclei, 1956-1962; 3 folders (Box 54)
    - 1956-1960 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - 1960-1962 (Box 54, Folder 3)
      Includes many preparation of ribosomes experiments; gel block and gel diffusion photographs.
  - Dische (H₂ SO4 - Cysteine), 1961 (Box 54)
    Reactions with thymus nuclei and with tris extracts of nuclei; includes some photocopied pages of H. Stierlin dissertation.
  - Amino acid penetration, 1961; 2 folders (Box 54)
    Folder 1 includes handwritten summary of Materials and Methods for experiments in both folders.
  - Immunization notes, 1961-1963 (Box 54)
  - Fluorescein and eosin dyes, 1961-1962 (Box 55)
  - Histone displacement using protamine, 1964; 2 folders (Box 55)
  - Histone extractions using alcohol - HC1, 1963-1964; 2 folders (Box 55, Folder 1-2)
  - Electrophoresis of histones from enzyme treated nuclei, 1965 (Box 55)
  - Uranium acetate combining experiments, 1965 (Box 55)
  - PCA experiments; electrophoresis, 1965 (Box 55)
    Includes dry cots; amino acid analyses.
  - HeLa cells, 1963-1966 (Box 55)
    Includes some correspondence; published papers by others on procedures.
  - HeLa cells, 1965-1966 (Box 56)
    Includes Fisher and Harris reprint on procedures.
  - HeLa cells - prints, 1966-1967 (Box 56)
    Prints from electron photomicrographs on HeLa chromosomes, cells, nuclei.
  - Nuclei extractions; electrophoresis of fractions, 1966 (Box 56)
    Includes electrophoresis prints.
  - Arthur Schindler (technician) Sephadex notes, 1964-1965 (Box 56)
  - Carolyn Burdick notes, 1964-1966; 3 folders (Box 56)
    - electrophoresis work, 1964
    - electrophoresis work, 1965
    - electrophoresis work, 1965-1966
  - Carolyn Burdick notes, 1966 (Box 57)
    Work all on electrophoresis; includes electrophoresis prints.
  - Ettie Rachloff, circa 1967 (Box 57)
    Includes 1 notebook of procedures; handwritten and typescript draft of "A simplified procedure for electrophoretic separation of calf thymus histones".
  - Non-histone chromatin protein in, 1966-1967 (Box 57)
    - Includes electrophoresis work and prints, 1966
    - Includes electrophoresis work, 1967
      (See Box 62 for photographs of electrophoresis work in album).
  - Histone records; storage, 1967 1969 1970 (Box 57)
  - Histone preparation; chromatin fractionation in, 1969-1970 (Box 57)
    - Chromatin fractionation; lysine-rich histone; cellex column, 1969 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Calf liver nuclei - nonidet (July 1970); thymus chromatin fractionation and isolated nuclei; citric acid nuclei, 1969-1970 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Protein analyses by Stanford Moore, 1969 (Box 57)
  - Lysine-rich histone yields, 1970 (Box 57)
    Rat liver and thymus experiments on yields of lysine-rich histone.
  - Histone kinase, 1970 (Box 57)
  - DNA experiments, 1969-1970 (Box 57)
  - HeLa cultures, 1970 (Box 57)
  - Phosphorus analyses, 1969 1970 1971 (Box 58)
  - CHO cells, 1970-1971 (Box 58)
  - DNase experiments, 1971-1973; 7 folders (Box 58)
    - General experiments, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Sucrose nuclei, 1971 1972 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Thymus nuclei + fragment of LRH (Lysine-rich histone, 1972 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Liver nuclei, 1971-1972 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Thymus nuclei: 80% Alc-HC1-Extr-DNase; phosphorylation, 1971-1972 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Frozen thymus citric acid nuclei, 1970 1971-1972 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - DNP, 1971-1973 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis, 1971 (Box 58)
  - Phosphorylation of LRH (lysine-rich histone), 1970-1972 (Box 58)
    A series of experiments by Bert Silverman under supervision of Alfred E. Mirsky in 11 folders:.
    - Histone phosphatase, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Dephosphorylation experiments, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Inorganic phosphate (Pi) miscellaneous, 1970 1971 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Alkaline, histone phosphatase; proteolytic activity, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Histone phosphatase; Pi experiments, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Pi - lysine-rich histone, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - RNA liver nuclei, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - New experimental notes, 1970 1971 (Box 58, Folder 8)
      - Electron micrographs, 1960-1972; 7; 7 folders
        Photographs and negatives of electron micrography.
        Arranged in chronological order where possible.
        - 38 Electron micrograph photographs and 73 negatives of liver nuclei and 1M sediment (nucleoli), 1960 (Box 60, Folder 1)
        - 214 Electron micrograph negatives -V. Littau - Alcohol-HC1 extractions of thymus nuclei. #255 - #2897, 1963 (Box 60, Folder 2)
          Lacks: 286-291; 293.
          - 348-366
          - 385-444
          - 449-488
          - 493-604
          - 620-695
          - 701-712
          - 741-832
          - 857-1228
          - 1241-2888
        - 54 Electron micrograph photographs (labelled Prints I - best plates) Alcohol-HC1 extractions of thymus nuclei, 1963 (Box 60, Folder 3)
          Includes some lab notes with observations by A. Schindler and Alfred E. Mirsky notes and summaries. Explanation included p.57. The above photographs (prints) are of V. Littau negatives.
        - 51 Electron micrograph photographs (labelled Prints II - mediocre plates) Alcohol-HC1 extractions of thymus nuclei, 1963 (Box 60, Folder 4)
          Explanation included p. 56. The above photographs (prints) are of V. Littau negatives.
        - 5 Electron micrograph photographs of calf thymus nuclei, undated (Box 60, Folder 5)
          Removed from lab poster.
        - 6 Electron micrograph photographs of calf thymus nuclei, undated (Box 60, Folder 6)
          Removed from lab poster on which heading read "Histones and the structure of chromatin".
        - [nd] 3 Electron micrograph photographs from Louisiana State University School of Medicine, Department of Anatomy (Box 60, Folder 7)
        - Electron micrograph photographs (prints) and negatives of Experiments I - X, 1969 February-1972 May
          Includes prints and negatives with numbered descriptive breakdown of different phases within each experiment when available. Experiments VIII, IX, X include some laboratory notes.
          - Experiment 1 Thymus nuclei, 1969 February 25; Total 12 prints (Box 61, Folder 1)
            - 1) Control, 2 prints
            - 2) Lysine-rich histone removed, 3 prints
            - 3) Add lysine-rich histone, 4 prints
            - 4) Add lysine-rich histone, 3 prints
          - Experiment II Histone removed - polylysine added, 1969 May 13; Total 38 prints; 2 duplicate prints; 68 negatives (Box 61, Folder 2)
            On back of each print and on each negative a number designation shown but no descriptive breakdown.
            - 1), 7 prints; 1 duplicate print; 12 negatives
            - 2), 12 prints; 18 negatives